Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) records, 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio-Visual Education Center (AVEC)
  - Film Scripts
    - First Aid for Head and Neck Injuries in Football (Box 26)
    - Goodbye to Captain Hook (Box 26)
    - Henry Ford Historical Film Collection (Box 26)
    - High School Band Day 1960 (Box 26)
    - Immediate Dental Prosthesis (Box 26)
    - Industrial Exhaust Systems (Box 26)
    - Introduction to Digital Logic, parts 1 & 2 (Box 26)
    - Knowledge, Wisdom, and the Courage to Serve (1967) (Box 26)
    - Locks of Sault Ste. Marie, The (Box 26)
    - Mechanism of Chip Formation (Box 26)
    - Michigan Rhapsody (1961 ?) (Box 26)
    - Micro-Circulation Studies (Box 26)
    - Old Spain on the Caribbean (Box 26)
    - Phoenix Project (ca. 1954) (Box 26)
    - Rehabilitation of a Paraplegic (Box 26)
    - Rice Farming in Japan (1952) (Box 26)
    - Rose Bowl 1972 (Box 26)
    - School Days (1959) (Box 26)
    - Solar Disk (1959) (Box 26)
    - Story of Maple Syrup (Box 26)
    - SELMA/QAS (Systems Engineering Laboratory-Markhov Analysis/Que Analyzer System) (Box 26)
    - Telling Stories to Children (Box 26)
    - We'll Remember Michigan (Box 26)
    - Wrestling Techniques (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous titles (Box 26)
- Newspaper Clippings
  Newspaper Clippings include news and feature articles and reviews from the local, national, and trade press. The clippings are arranged in chronological and topical files.
  - 1950-1951 (Box 27)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 27)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 27)
  - 1953-1954 (Box 27)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 27)
  - 1959-1961, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Awards (Box 28)
    - 1956-1965 (Box 28)
    - 1966-1972 (Box 28)
  - Garrison, Garnet (Box 28)
  - Medical Television (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1950-1960 (Box 28)
    - 1954-1959, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 28)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 28)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 28)
    - 1974-1987 (Box 28)
  - Salk Polio Vaccine Announcement 1955 (Box 28)
  - Series I and B Programs
    - 1954-1957, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - 1962-1967 (Box 28)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 28)
  - Trigger Films 1971-1974 (Box 28)
  - WPAG TV 1954-1956 (Box 28)
- Music Releases
  Music Releases are releases from music publishers permitting use of musical pieces in programs in Series B and I. Arrangement is by program title in Series I and by program number in Series B.
  - Releases (Box 29)
- Photographs / Negatives
  The collection contains a substantial number of Photographs, both negatives and prints. These include stills of television productions; publicity photos; portraits of faculty participants in programs; images of the TVC studios, equipment and staff; and photos of special events recorded by the TVC, including the Salk polio vaccine press conference, Lyndon Johnson's 1964 commencement address, and Martin Luther King, Jr.'s appearance at Hill Auditorium.
  The photographs are arranged into several categories; by television program or series, in chronological sequence, or in topical files. Individual photographs are often not identified. If a photograph is identified by television series or program, it is sometimes possible to determine the identity of individuals by consulting the press releases.
  - Series A (Box 30)
  - Series B
    - Chronological, 5 folders (Box 30)
  - Series H
    - Alphabetical (by program title) (Box 30)
  - Series I
    - American Consumer-Plays of Shakespeare (Box 31)
    - Public Arts-Your Child's First Years (Box 32)
    - Chronological 1954-1958 (Box 32)
  - Speech Dept. Labs and Dramas 1948-1951 (Box 33)
  - Early WWJ-TV Teletours and Telecourses (Box 33)
  - WWJ-TV Teletour 1950-1954 (Box 33)
  - "Contrite Spirit" TV Drama 1953 (Box 33)
  - WPAG Television circa 1953-1955 (Box 33)
  - TV Center Staff, Studio, and Equipment circa 1949-1970, 6 folders (Box 33)
  - Awards (Box 33)
  - Special Events and Activities
    - President Ruthven's Farm (Box 33)
    - Salk Vaccine Press Conference 1954 (Box 33)
    - 1964 Commencement, Lyndon B. Johnson (Box 33)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. at Hill Auditorium (Box 33)
    - Summer Field Trips 1952
      - Biological Station (Box 33)
      - Fresh Air Camp (Box 33)
      - Geography Camp (Box 33)
    - Women's Hospital-Delivery Room (Box 33)
    - Medical Color TV (Box 33)
    - Giancarlo Menotti at the Music School (Box 33)
    - ICLE (Box 33)
    - MPATI (Box 33)
    - Winter Commencement-Harlan Hatcher (Box 33)
- Photo negatives
  - Series I (Box 34)
  - Series A (Box 34)
  - Series B (Box 34)
  - Chronological 1953-1958 (Box 35)
- Slides
  - Campus Buildings
    - Administration Building, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Alumni Hall, 2 slides (Box 34)
    - Angell Hall, 5 slides (Box 34)
    - Burton Tower, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Campus Roof Tops, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Diag, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - East Engineering, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Hill Auditorium, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Law Quad, 9 slides (Box 34)
    - Michigan Union, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Music School (old), 1 slides (Box 34)
    - Student Activities Building, 1 slides (Box 34)
    - West Physics, 1 slides (Box 34)
  - General Motors Technical Center, 21 slides (Box 33)
- Films and videotapes
  The Films and Videotapes in the Media Resources Center record group include ca. 1500 kinescope films and videotapes, 1948-1986, of television programs on academic topics, current affairs, the state of Michigan, and the University of Michigan; also ca. 1000 reels of 16 mm film and videotapes, 1952-ca. 1980, of documentary footage of events at the University of Michigan including commencements, building dedications, award ceremonies, classroom and laboratory scenes, homecoming, athletic events and marching band performances, student demonstrations, and general campus scenes.
  The films and videotapes in the Michigan Media collection were appraised and only a portion have been selected for permanent retention by the Bentley Historical Library. A number of appraisal criteria were used in determining which television programs and films were retained:
  subject matter relating to the University of Michigan
  subject matter relating to the state of Michigan
  subject matter of general, national interest
  participation of prominent UM faculty or staff
  participation of prominent Michigan personalities
  participation of persons of national or international significance
  programs marking significant technical or artistic developments at Michigan Media
  award winning programs.
  The television programs and films are described in detail in a companion "Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) Films and Videotapes". The arrangement of that finding aid is by television series, comparable to the arrangement of the scripts. The description of each program includes the title, episode or program number if part of a multi-part program, a brief summary of program content, a list of "stars," and negative, positive and cassette numbers as appropriate. There is also an index to individuals appearing in programs.
  The Archival Film series is also described in "Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) Films and Videotex." This series is made up of film footage documenting a variety of university and community events. Some of this film was shot as stock footage for use in television programs or films. Much of it, however, was produced as part of an effort to build a film archive of the university. Individual titles range from 20 to 1000 feet in length and may include negatives, prints, and work prints that have been cut up and spliced.
  The description of each film includes the film number, a brief description of the content of the film, list of persons appearing on the film, information on length, polarity, sound and color characteristics, and occasional notes. The Film File series and the Audio-Visual Film File series are similar to the Archival series. They include documentary footage about the university and footage shot for inclusion in TVC and AVEC productions. There are personal name and subject indexes for the archival and Film File series.
  - Television Programs, 1300 titles approximate
  - Audio-Visual Education Center Films, 72 titles
  - "Archives" Film, 600 titles approximate
  - "Film File", 265 titles approximate